<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Peter Indiola</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Peter Indiola</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:06:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterindiola.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Will AI Replace Front-End Developers?</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/posts/will-ai-replace-front-end-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:06:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/posts/will-ai-replace-front-end-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s been a hot debate on Reddit about AI replacing front-end developers. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been in the industry coding websites for years, I wanted to share my perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ais-impact-on-front-end-development">AI&amp;rsquo;s Impact on Front-End Development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you think about it, AI is like a super-powered Google search combined with those old Visual Studio tools, ReSharper from 2008 showing my age here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fun fact: I still remember my first Stack Overflow question. After trying EVERYTHING and pulling my hair out, I finally worked up the courage to post. And wow&amp;hellip; those comments were brutal! &amp;ldquo;Did you even try Google?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;RTFM!&amp;rdquo; I was so discouraged I didn&amp;rsquo;t post again for years. 😅 Now I just ask AI the &amp;ldquo;dumb questions&amp;rdquo; without judgment - what a time to be alive!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 Year End Retro</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/posts/2024-year-end-retro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:58:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/posts/2024-year-end-retro/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the year ends, I’ve been thinking about everything that’s happened—the good, the bad, and what I’ve learned. Things didn’t always go the way I wanted, but the surprises helped me grow in ways I didn’t expect. They’ve also set me up for what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="dealing-with-challenges-and-finding-hope">Dealing with challenges and finding hope&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Moving my kids back to the Philippines was tough. Things weren’t working out as planned, and bringing them back home wasn’t what I had in mind. But it was the right choice for our family. It showed me that life can be unpredictable, and you just have to roll with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/pages/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, I’m Peter! I’m a software developer with 16 years of experience. I’m a husband, dad of three, and a runner who loves balancing tech, family, and staying active. I enjoy solving problems, sharing knowledge, and building cool stuff.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>