<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Peter Indiola - Filipino Software Developer &amp; Tech Writer</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Peter Indiola - Filipino Software Developer &amp; Tech Writer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 10:27:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterindiola.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Bother Learning to Code When AI Exists?</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/posts/why-bother-learning-to-code-when-ai-exists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 10:27:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/posts/why-bother-learning-to-code-when-ai-exists/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Why do you still need to study that? We have AI now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this happened recently and I can&amp;rsquo;t stop thinking about it. My coworker saw me watching YouTube videos about SwiftUI and he&amp;rsquo;s like&amp;hellip; why? Just why would you bother learning SwiftUI with AI around?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, fair question I guess. I&amp;rsquo;m doing ReactJS on web and React Native for mobile development. In this 2025 tech market, I should probably be learning system design or whatever - you need to know everything instead of being a generalist to stay marketable. When I told him I already know that stuff, he&amp;rsquo;s like yeah okay but still. The look on his face though. Like I was doing something completely pointless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will AI Replace Front-End Developers?</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/posts/will-ai-replace-front-end-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:06:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/posts/will-ai-replace-front-end-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>So there&amp;rsquo;s been this huge debate on Reddit about AI replacing front-end developers. I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding websites for years now and honestly, I had to chime in with my thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know what&amp;rsquo;s funny? AI feels like a super-powered Google search mixed with those old Visual Studio tools. Remember ReSharper from like 2008? Yeah, showing my age here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still cringe thinking about my first Stack Overflow question. I tried everything, pulled my hair out for hours, finally got the courage to post and&amp;hellip; man, those comments were savage. &amp;ldquo;Did you even try Google?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;RTFM!&amp;rdquo; I was so discouraged I didn&amp;rsquo;t post again for years. Now I just ask AI all my dumb questions without getting roasted. What a time to be alive, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 Year End Retro</title><link>https://peterindiola.com/posts/2024-year-end-retro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:58:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peterindiola.com/posts/2024-year-end-retro/</guid><description>&lt;p>2024 is almost over and wow, what a year. Definitely not what I expected when it started but then again, when does life ever go according to plan?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hardest thing this year was having to move my kids back to the Philippines. That really sucked. We tried making things work here in Singapore but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening the way we hoped. Had to make the tough call to send them home. Still feels weird saying that but it was the right choice for everyone. Sometimes being a parent means making decisions that hurt but are necessary.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>